-我不知道...  -什么
- Oh, I don't know. - What?
照狗的年纪来算
Well, as old as he is in dog years...
你认为史奴比  还能飞这个玩意儿吗
do you think Snoopy should still be allowed to fly this thing?
瑞秋
Rachel?
什么事
Yeah?
记得你刚来的时候
You remember when you first came here,
有另外一个服务员训练了你两周吗
how you spent two weeks getting trained by another waitress?
当然  是要我训练新人吗
Sure! Do you need me to train somebody new?
问得好
Good one.
其实是泰瑞要你再受训一次
Actually, Terry wants you to take the training again.
什么时候都可以
Whenever.
你相信这种事吗
Do you believe that?
相信
Yeah.
一共是两盒杏仁饼干
So that's two boxes of the Holiday Macaroons.
我代表美国棕鸟向你致敬
On behalf of the Brown Birds of America, I salute you.
承认吧  钱德勒  你不会反手击球
Just admit it. Chandler, you have no backhand.
对不起小鬼  我反手击球很厉窖
Excuse me, little one. I have a very solid backhand.
像个女人一样掩面大叫
Shielding your face and shrieking like a girl...
不叫反手击球
is not a backhand.
我的叫声
I was shrieking...
像海军
like a Marine.
好  看我示范冠军选手的三个P
All right, here, watch me execute the three P's of championship play.
力量
Power...
准头
precision...
架式
and panache.
你害一个小女孩的腿骨折
You broke a little girl's leg?
我知道  我很难过  行吗
I know. I feel horrible, okay?
报上说有个木偶昨晚在芝麻街遭遇重击
It says here that a Muppet got whacked on Sesame Street last night.
你昨晚十点左右人在哪里
Where exactly were you around 10-ish?
我要去看她
I'm gonna go see her.
我想带点东西给她  她会喜欢什么呢
I wanna bring her something. What do you think she'd like?
凯蒂猫的玩偶
Maybe a Hello Kitty doll?
走路的能力
The ability to walk?
我得回去接受训练了
I'm gonna get back to retraining.
好吧  再见各位
All right. See you, guys.
小心啊孩子们  他来了
Look out, kids! He's coming!
我得去卖圣诞树了
I gotta go sell some Christmas trees.
卖得开心点  等等  不要去
Have fun. Oh, wait! No, don't!
我忘了  我现在完全反对这件事
I forgot. I am totally against that now.
什么  反对我有工作吗
What? Me having a job?
不  我反对无辜的树木
No, I am against innocent trees
在其青春正盛的时候被砍下
being cut down in their prime...
而尸体还被装饰得怪模怪样
and their corpses grotesquely dressed...
挂上一堆金箔和闪灯
in, like, tinsel and twinkly lights.
你晚上睡得好吗
How do you sleep at night?
我拖着树  走来走去累得要命
Well, I'm pretty tired from lugging the trees around.
菲比  你完全搞错了
Hey, Phoebe, listen, you got this all wrong.
那些树生来就是要当圣诞树的
Those trees were born to be Christmas trees.
通过为人们带来欢乐来实现生命的价值
They're fulfilling their life purpose by making people happy.
真的
Really?
没错
Yes!
对  这些树也很高兴
Yes, and the trees are happy too...
因为对大多数的树来说  这是它们
because for most of them, it's their only...
见识纽约的唯一机会
chance to see New York.
送完饮料之后  把空盘子...
After you deliver the drinks, you take the empty tray
甘瑟  拜托  我在这里做了两年半
Gunther, please. I have worked here for two and a half years.
我知道空盘子要放在这里
I know the empty trays go over there.
放在这里怎么样
What if you put them here?
这倒是个好主意
You know, that's actually a really good idea.
离马克杯比较近
Because that way they'll be closer to the mugs.
你应该要其他服务生也照办
You know what? You should have the other waitresses do that too.
她们本来就是这么放的
They already do.
所以她们管这里叫盘子区
That's why they call it the tray spot.
天哪  我总听她们说这个
Jeez, I always heard them talk about that.
我还以为是她们参加的俱乐部  天哪
I sort of just thought it was, like, a club they went to. Oh, God.
-对不起  -没关系
- I'm sorry. - It's all right.
甜心
Sweetheart.
你一定很高兴吧
So this must be kind of neat for you, huh?
你爸爸说你可以不用上学
Your dad tells me you get a couple days off school...
也不必再去卖饼干了
and you don't have to sell those cookies anymore.
我很想去卖饼干
Well, I kind of wanted to sell the cookies.
卖最多饼干的人可以参加太空营
The girl who sells the most wins a trip to Space Camp...
坐上真正的太空飞船
and gets to sit in a real space shuttle.
你很喜欢太空的东西啊
You really like all this space stuff, huh?
是的  我爸爸说
Yeah, my dad says
如果我帮他清洁公寓的时间
if I'd spend as much time helping him clean apartments...
和我做太空白日梦的时间一样多
as I do daydreaming about outer space...
他就有钱去泰姬陵了
he'd be able to afford a trip to the Taj Mahal.
我想要清洁非常多的公寓
I think you'd have to clean a whole lot of apartments
才有钱去印度
to go all the way to India.
不  是大西洋城的赌场
No. The one in Atlantic City.
爸爸喜欢玩老虎机
Dad loves the slots.
他说会把奶奶留给我上大学的钱翻倍
He says he's gonna double the college money my grandma left me.
那就祝爸爸好运吧
Well, good luck to Dad.
需要再卖多少盒饼干才能获胜
Say, how many more boxes would you have to sell in order to win?
去年的冠军卖了475盒
The girl who won last year sold 475.
我到目前为止卖了75盒
So far, I've sold 75.
还有四百盒
Four hundred, huh?
应该不难
Well, that sounds doable.
一盒多少钱
How much are the boxes?
五块钱
Five dollars a box.
二等奖是什么
And what is second prize?
十速自行车
A 10-speed bike.
但我宁可要爸爸不能变卖的东西
But I'd rather have something my dad couldn't sell.
这也对
That makes sense.
帮我一个忙好吗  希望不会麻烦你
Could you do me one favor? If it's not too much trouble.
好的  莎拉  你尽管说
Yeah, Sarah. Anything.
帮我把窗帘拉开好吗
Could you pull the curtains open for me?
太空人会上电视新闻
The astronauts from space ship are gonna be on the news.
因为我们没有电视  所以对面的小姐
Since we don't have a TV, so the lady across the alley...
说她会把她的电视推到窗口让我看
said she'd push hers up to her window so I can watch it.
什么事
Yes?
你好  我是卖棕鸟饼干的
Hi. I'm selling Brown Bird cookies.
你不是棕鸟队员  我可以从猫眼里看到你
You're no Brown Bird. I can see you through my peephole.
你好  我是棕鸟的荣誉队员
Hi. I'm an honorary Brown Bird.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
是说我可以卖饼干
It means that I can sell cookies,
但不能在别人家过夜
but I'm not invited to sleepovers.
我按个按钮就能报警
I can dial 911 at the press of a button, you know.
快走
Now, go away!
拜托  我是为了一个贫穷的小女孩
Please, please. It's for a poor little girl...
她最大的心愿就是参加太空营
who wants to go to Space Camp more than anything in the world.
我按钮了
I'm pressing.
警察马上就来了
A policeman is on his way.
好的  好的  我马上走
Okay, okay! I'm going, I'm going.
我还看得到你
I can still see you!
好啦
All right!
你来这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
我把你的话想了很久
I thought a lot about what you said...
我发觉也许我是有点太主观了
and I realize maybe I was a little judgmental.
对  可是...
Yeah. Oh, but, oh.
菲比  记住
Now, now, Phoebe, remember...
它们只是在实现他们的圣诞
they're just fulfilling their Christmas
-宿命  是的  -没错
- Destiny. Yes. - Sure.
那棵看起来好像很空虚
That one doesn't look very fulfilled.
那是老树了  他只是把树拿到后面罢了
That's one of the old ones. He's just taking it to the back.
你们把老树放在后面
You keep the old ones in the back?
真是年龄歧视
That is so ageist.
这样才有地方放新鲜的树
We have to make room for the fresh ones.
那老的怎么办
So what happens to the old guys?
拿去切碎
Well, they go into the chipper.
我有种非常不祥的预感
I have a feeling that's not as happy as it sounds.
不要
No, no!
这些是你们最喜欢的圣诞人物的形状
And these come in the shapes of your favorite Christmas characters.
圣诞老人  鲁道夫  和耶稣宝宝
Santa, Rudolph and Baby Jesus.
我要一盒奶油馅的耶稣宝宝
All right, I'll take a box of the cream-filled Jesuses.
等等  就买一盒
Wait a minute, one box?
这可是为了送一个可怜的小女孩去太空营啊
Come on, I'm trying to send a poor little girl to Space Camp.
我算你五盒  钱德勒  你呢
I'm putting you down for 5 boxes. Chandler, what about you?
好吧  你有没有椰子口味的神
All right. Do you have any coconut-flavored deities?
没有  但光明节烛台形状的有椰子口味
No, but there's coconut in the Hanukkah Menorah-eos.
这样吧  我算你八盒
I'll tell you what. I'll put you down for 8 boxes.
一晚一盒
One for each night.
莫妮卡
Mon?
好吧  我要一盒薄荷口味的
All right, I'll take one box of the Mint Treasures.
一盒就好了
One, and that's it.
我参加棕鸟之后就胖了
I started gaining weight after I joined the Brown Birds.
记得吗  爸爸买光了我的饼干
Remember? Dad bought every one of my boxes
我全吃掉了
and I ate them all.
不  莫妮卡  爸不得不买下所有饼干
No, Mon. Dad had to buy every one of your boxes...
因为你全吃光了
because you ate them all.
但是  我确定这次一定不会这样了
But, you know, I'm sure that's not gonna happen this time.
不如我给你算三盒薄荷
Why don't I just put you down for 3 of Mint Treasures
两盒鲁道夫吧
and just a couple of Rudolphs?
不要
No.
好啦  你知道你很想吃
Oh, come on, now. You know you want them.
不要这样
Don't do this.
这样吧  莫妮卡  第一盒算我送你的
I'll tell you what, Mon. I'll give you the first box for free.
老天  我得走了
Oh, God! I gotta go!
来嘛  好孩子都吃这种饼干
Come on! All the cool kids are eating them.
等你待会儿有空的时候
And when you have a second later,
我会告诉你为什么不能
I wanna show you why we don't just trap spiders...
把蜘蛛困在马克杯底下就算了
under coffee mugs and leave them there.
我痛恨这工作  却还要努力改进
I'm training to be better at a job that I hate.
我的人生算是完了
My life officially sucks!
瑞秋  这不是暂时性的工作吗
But Rach, wasn't this supposed to be a temporary thing?
我以为你的目标是打入时装界
I thought you wanted to do fashion stuff.
对  我还在朝目标前进
Yeah, I'm still pursuing that.
你是怎么前进的
How, exactly, are you pursuing that?
除了两年前寄过简历以外
You know, other than sending out resumes, like, what? Two years ago?
我还传达了
Well, I'm also sending out...
好点子
good thoughts.
要我说  只要你还保有这份工作
If you ask me, as long as you got this job...
就没有找新工作的动机
you got nothing pushing you to get another one.
你需要的是恐惧
You need The Fear.
-恐惧  -他说得对
- The Fear? - He's right.
辞掉这份工作才有动机
If you quit this job, you then have motivation
追求你心目中理想的工作
to go after a job you really want.
你为何还在做你讨厌的工作
Then how come you still at a job that you hate?
干嘛不辞职来产生恐惧
Why don't you quit and get The Fear?
因为我太害怕了
Because I'm too afraid.
我不知道
I don't know.
我愿意不顾一切的为设计师
I mean, I'd give anything to work for a designer,
或采购人工作
you know, or a buyer.
我不想到了30岁还在这里工作
I just don't want to be 30 and still work here.
对  那要比28岁还在这工作惨多了
Yeah, that'd be much worse than being 28 and still working here.
-瑞秋  -干嘛
- Rachel? - Yeah.
提醒我跟你复习哪壶是低因咖啡
Remind me to review with you which pot is decaf
哪壶是普通的
and which is regular.
看把手看不出来吗
Can't I just look at the handles on them?
想得美
You would think.
好了  甘瑟  你知道吗
Okay, fine. Gunther, you know what?
我是个很差劲的服务生
I am a terrible waitress.
你知道这是为什么吗  因为我不在乎
Do you know why I'm a terrible waitress? Because I don't care.
我不在乎  我不在乎哪壶是普通咖啡
I don't care. I don't care which pot is regular
哪壶是低因咖啡
and which pot is decaf.
我不在乎盘子区在哪里
I don't care where the tray spot is.
我就是不在乎  这不是我想做的工作
I just don't care. This is not what I want to do.
所以我想我不该再做下去了
So I don't think I should do it anymore.
-我正式提出辞呈  -什么
- I'm giving my week's notice. - What?
甘瑟  我辞职
Gunther, I quit.
这表示以后喝咖啡要付钱了吗
Does this mean we have to start paying for coffee?
好  12
Okay, twelve.
干嘛
What?
我拼出了"咪咪"
I spelled out "boobies".
罗斯  再给我一盒薄荷口味的好吗
Ross, Put me down for another box of the Mint Treasures, okay?
薄荷饼干在哪里
Where are the Mint Treasures?
没有了  都卖光了
We're out. I sold them all.
什么
What?
莫妮卡  我不能再让你吃下去了
Monica, I'm cutting you off.
不行  不要
No, No.
再给我两盒就好
Just a couple more boxes.
这也没什么  我很好
It's no big deal, all right? I'm cool.
你得帮我再弄两盒
You gotta help me with a couple more boxes!
莫妮卡  看看你自己  你脖子上还有饼干
Mon, look at yourself. You have cookie on your neck.
老天
Oh, God!
-你卖了多少盒了  -你看
- So how many you sold so far? - Check this out.
老天  你怎么办到的
Oh, my God! How did you do that?
那天晚上  我离开博物馆的时候
Okay, the other night I was leaving the museum...
天文馆正在放镭射佛洛依德
just as Laser Floyd was letting out of the planetarium.
我随随便便就卖了50盒
Without even trying, I sold 50 boxes!
这时我想到
That's when it occurred to me.
成功的关键就是"饥饿感"
The key to my success: The munchies.
所以我开始在午夜时分去纽约大学的宿舍
So I started hitting the NYU dorms around midnight.
那饼干简直是论箱卖
I am selling cookies by the case.
他们叫我"饼干佬"
They call me "Cookie Dude"!
放下手边的事
Okay, stop what you're doing.
我需要人帮我塞信封  舔邮票...
I need envelope stuffers, I need stamp lickers....
谁帮你写的简历
Who did these resumes for you?
我  用我的电脑写的
Me. On my computer.
你这字体还真够大的
You sure used a large font.
对  "咖啡馆的服务生"
Yeah. Well, "Waitress at a Coffeehouse"...
和"啦啦队副队长"占不了多少空间
and "Cheer Squad Co-Captain" only took up so much room.
真有趣
Hey, that's funny!
你好有趣  钱德勒  你有趣极了
You're funny, Chandler! You're a funny guy!
知道还有哪件事有趣吗
You know what else is funny?
我说错了什么吗
Something else I might have said?
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
不是你在我毫无后路的时候
Weren't you the guy that told me to quit my job...
叫我辞职的吗
when I had absolutely nothing else to do?
亲爱的  别激动  事情会顺利的
Sweetie, calm down. It's gonna be okay.
不会的  罗斯  明天是我最后一天上班
No, it's not gonna be okay, Ross. Tomorrow is my last day...
而我到现在还毫无进展
and I don't have a lead.
你知道吗  我要打电话给甘瑟
You know what? I'm just gonna call Gunther...
说我不辞职了
and tell him I'm not quitting.
你不能向恐惧投降
You don't want to give in to The Fear.
去你的和你那愚蠢的恐惧  我讨厌你的恐惧
You and your stupid Fear! I hate your Fear!
我要把你和你的恐惧...
I would like to take you and your Fear...
嘿  我有好消息
Hey! I got great news!
快跑乔伊  逃命去吧
Run, Joey! Run for your life!
他干嘛
What?
瑞秋  你听说过"运幸时装"吗
Rach, listen. Have you ever heard of Fortunata Fashions?
没有
No.
我老爸在那里做水管工
My old man's doing a plumbing job down there
听说那里要招人
and he heard they have an opening.
要他帮你安排面试吗
So, you want me to see if he could get you an interview?
天哪我要  太好了  你真好  乔伊
Oh, my God, yes! I would love that! That's so sweet, Joey.
应该的
Not a problem.
现在告诉你们好消息
And now, for the great news.
刚才那个不是好消息吗
That wasn't the great news?
除非你们觉得比这个更好
Only if you think it's better than this.
雪花罐
Snow-in-a-Can!
我在工作的地方拿的
I got it at work.
莫妮卡  要我装饰窗户吗
Mon, you want me to decorate the window?
看起来有圣诞的感觉
Give it kind of a Christmas looky?
圣诞饼干
Christmas cookie?
这是一棵道格拉斯冷杉
Okay, and this one here's a Douglas fir.
这个比较贵一点  但也比较香
Now, it's a little more money, but you get a nicer smell.
看起来不错  我买了
Looks good. I'll take it.
等等  不要  不要买那棵
Wait, wait. No, no! You don't want that one!
不  你可以买这棵超棒的棕色树
No, no. You can have this cool brown one.
这树都快死了
It's almost dead.
所以非买不可
Okay, that's why you have to buy it,
让它完成它的圣诞宿命
so that it can fulfill its Christmas destiny.
不然他们就会切碎它  告诉他  乔伊
Otherwise, they'll throw it into the chipper. Tell him, Joey.
对  无法完成圣诞宿命的树
Yeah, the trees that don't fulfill their Christmas destiny...
就要拿去切碎
are thrown in the chipper.
我还是再看看吧
I think I'm gonna look around a little bit more.
菲比  你不能再这样了  我是赚佣金的
Pheebs, you gotta stop doing this. I'm working on commission here!
两位  我来挑一棵圣诞树
Hey guys, I'm here to pick out my Christmas tree.
别看了  就买这棵
Well, look no further! This one's yours!
这是我去年丢掉的那棵吗
Is this the one that I threw out last year?
知道吗  算了  大家都想买绿树
Well, you know what, never mind! Everybody wants to have a green one!
对不起  我也不想这么情绪化
Sorry, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to get so emotional.
只是过节就是让人很难受
I guess it's just the holidays are just hard.
亲爱的  是因为
Oh, honey. Is that because
你母亲在圣诞节过世的原因吗
your mom died around Christmas?
我还没想到那件事呢
I wasn't even thinking about that.
你好  你卖了多少
Hi there. How many did you sell?
我不告诉你  你是害莎拉断腿的坏人
I'm not gonna tell you. You're the bad man who broke Sarah's leg.
那是意外  好吗
Hey, now. That was an accident, okay?
你是个大斗蛋
You're a big scrud.
什么是斗蛋
What's a scrud?
照镜子就看到了  斗蛋
Why don't you look in the mirror, scrud?
我不用照镜子  我看你就行了
I don't have to. I can just look at you.
好了  各位小女孩
All right, girls...
和大男人
and man.
我们看看大家的总成绩
Let's see your final tallies.
黛比
Debbie.
321盒饼干  很好
Three hundred and twenty-one boxes of cookies. Very nice.
还不够好
Not nice enough.
夏拉
Charla.
278盒
Two hundred and seventy-eight.
对不起亲爱的  但还算不错
Sorry, dear, but still good.
对斗蛋来说是不错
Good for a scrud.
你呢  伊莉莎白
Yes, Elizabeth.
871盒
Eight hundred and seventy-one.
胡扯
That's crap!
棕鸟领队
Sister Brown Bird.
做得好
Good going.
下一个是谁
Who's next?
-你好  -你好
- Hi there. - Hi.
替代莎拉的
And batting for Sarah...
罗斯·盖勒
Ross Geller.
872盒
Eight hundred and seventy-two.
不过看样子你自己买了一大堆饼干
Although, it looks like you bought an awful lot of cookies yourself.
那是因为我的医生说我有
That is because my doctor says that I have...
很严重的
a very serious...
果仁糖
nougat...
不足
deficiency.
把事情的经过告诉我们  棕鸟罗斯
Tell us what happened, Brown Bird Ross.
我输了  有个小女孩
I lost. Some little girl
把制服借给19岁的姐姐
loaned her uniform to her 19-year-old sister...
她到尼米兹号航母上卖掉了两千多盒
who went down to the U.S.S. Nimitz and sold over 2000 boxes.
-面试怎么样  -我搞砸了
- How'd the interview go? - Oh, I blew it.
连我都不会请自己
I wouldn't have even hired me.
过来  过来吧亲爱的
Come here, come here sweetie.
听我说
Listen...
找到工作之前  要面试一千次
you're gonna go on, like, 1000 interviews before you get a job.
本想安慰你  说出来变了味道
That's not how that was supposed to come out.
这是最糟糕的圣诞节
This is just the worst Christmas ever.
瑞秋
You know what, Rach.
也许你应该留在咖啡馆
Maybe you should just you know stay here at the coffeehouse.
不行  太迟了  泰瑞已经请了那个女孩
I can't. It's too late. Terry already hired that girl over there.
你们看看她
Look at her.
她还有当服务生的经验
She's even got waitress experience.
昨天晚上  她还
Last night she was...
教大家把
teaching everybody how to make...
餐巾
napkins...
折成
into....
她说的是"天鹅"
That word was "swans."
看到酒醉的圣诞老人尿裤子
Well, seeing that drunk Santa wet himself
我的圣诞节可真欢乐
really perked up my Christmas.
我的天
Oh, my God!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
你们救了它们
You saved them! You guys!
老天  你们太棒了
Oh, God, you're the best!
好像是《活死人之夜》之圣诞树篇
Looks like Night of the Living Dead Christmas Trees.
喂
Hello?
对  我就是
Yeah, this is she.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding!
谢谢  我爱你
Oh, thank you! I love you!
当然啦  大家都爱开玩笑的人
Sure, everybody loves a kidder.
我找到工作了
I got the job!
太好了
That's great.
上帝保佑我们大家
God bless us, everyone!
好了  这是我最后一次端咖啡
Here we go. I'm serving my last cup of coffee.
给你
There you go.
用心品尝吧
Enjoy.
-我该告诉她我要的是茶吗  -不要说
- Should I tell her I ordered tea? - No.
打扰下  各位
Excuse me, everyone?
这是我在这里工作的最后一夜
This is my last night working here...
我只想说
and I just wanted to say...
我在这里交了一些好朋友
that I made some really good friends here.
现在是向前走的时候了
And it's just time to move on.
我无意冒犯  继续在这里工作的人
And no offense to everybody who still works here...
但你们不知道我多庆幸
but you have no idea how good it feels to say...
可以在这一刻说
that as of this moment...
我再也不必冲咖啡了
I will never have to make coffee again.
老卡普兰先生喜欢喝浓咖啡
Now, Mr. IKaplan Sr. Iikes his coffee strong.
所以一包不够  要用两包
So you want to use two bags instead of one.
注意听好了  这里很需要技巧
See. Now, pay attention, because this part's tricky.
有些人的滤纸只用一次
See, some people use filters just once....
我很遗憾你不能参加太空营
I'm sorry you didn't get to go to Space Camp...
我希望这个或许能帮我补偿你  好吗
and I'm hoping that maybe somehow this may help make up for it. Okay?
接下来是
Presenting...
莎拉·图多的私人特别太空营
Sarah Tuddle's Private Very Special Space Camp!
盖勒先生  其实你不必这么做的
Really, Mr. Geller, you don't have to do this.
别客气  来吧
Oh, come on, here we go!
准备倒数
Stand by for mission countdown!
十
Ten.
九
Nine.
八
Eight.
好  发射
Okay, blast off!
我是外星人  我是外星人
I'm an alien! I'm an alien!
不  小行星来了
Oh, no! An asteroid!